[
  {
    "question": "Knitting is a fully observable, episodic, stochastic, static and exciting agent environment.",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Procedural attachment is used in semantic networks.",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ontology is not a key component in simple-reflex agents.",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Recall is an evaluation metric used in information retrieval that measures the proportion of returned documents that are truly relevant",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Simulated annealing is a local search method.",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Term Frequency (TF) defines the count of a term t in a collection of documents.",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A common heuristic function for 8-puzzle game is Manhattan distance which is the sum of the distances of the tiles to their goal positions.",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "If both H1 and H2 are admissible heuristics for a problem and H2 < H1, then H2 is a better heuristic.",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "An agent must think like a human in order to pass the Turing test.",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Iterative deepening search is optimal if step-costs is a constant, the search-space is finite and a goal exists.",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Suppose the following action schema in a planning system for 8-puzzle.<math display=\"block\"><mi>Action</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>Slide</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>t</mi><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>,</mo></math><math display=\"block\"><mtext>PRECOND:</mtext><mo> </mo><mi>On</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>t</mi><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2227;</mo><mi>Tile</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>t</mi><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2227;</mo><mi>Blank</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2227;</mo><mi>Adjacent</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo></math><math display=\"block\"><mtext>EFFECT:</mtext><mo> </mo><mi>On</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>t</mi><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2227;</mo><mi>Blank</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2227;</mo><mo>&#xAC;</mo><mi>On</mi><mo>(</mo><mi>t</mi><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2227;</mo><mo>&#xAC;</mo><mi>Blank</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>)</mo></math>Which of the following needs to be removed from the action schema in order to get \"number-of-misplaced-tiles\" heuristic?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "<math><mi>Blank</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>)</mo></math>",
      "<math><mi>Blank</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo></math>",
      "<math><mi>Adjacent</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo></math>",
      "<math><mi>Blank</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo><mo>&#x2227;</mo><mi>Adjacent</mi><mo>(</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>s</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>)</mo></math>",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We look at a Constraint Satisfaction Problem (CSP) with the three variables <math><mi>X</mi></math>, <math><mi>Y</mi></math> and <math><mi>Z</mi></math>. Let the domain for each of these variables be the set of integers from 1 to 3: <math><msub><mi>D</mi><mi>X</mi></msub> = <msub><mi>D</mi><mi>Y</mi></msub> = <msub><mi>D</mi><mi>Z</mi></msub> = {1, 2, 3}</math>. Let the following binary constraint <math><msub><mi>C</mi><mrow><mi>X</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>Y</mi></mrow></msub></math> apply between <math><mi>X</mi></math> and <math><mi>Y</mi></math>, and <math><msub><mi>C</mi><mrow><mi>Y</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>Z</mi></mrow></msub></math> between <math><mi>Y</mi></math> and <math><mi>Z</mi></math>:<math display=\"block\"><msub><mi>C</mi><mrow><mi>X</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>Y</mi></mrow></msub> = [(1, 1), (2, 1), (2, 2), (3, 1), (3, 2), (3, 3)]</math><math display=\"block\"><msub><mi>C</mi><mrow><mi>Y</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>Z</mi></mrow></msub> = [(2,1), (3,1), (3,2)]</math>After running AC-3, what is the domain of <math><mi>X</mi></math>?",
    "answers": [1],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "<math>{1,2,3}</math>",
      "<math>{2,3}</math>",
      "<math>{1,3}</math>",
      "<math>{1,2}</math>",
      "<math>{1}</math>",
      "<math>{2}</math>",
      "<math>{3}</math>",
      "<math>{}</math>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We look at a Constraint Satisfaction Problem (CSP) with the three variables <math><mi>X</mi></math>, <math><mi>Y</mi></math> and <math><mi>Z</mi></math>. Let the domain for each of these variables be the set of integers from 1 to 3: <math><msub><mi>D</mi><mi>X</mi></msub> = <msub><mi>D</mi><mi>Y</mi></msub> = <msub><mi>D</mi><mi>Z</mi></msub> = {1, 2, 3}</math>. Let the following binary constraint <math><msub><mi>C</mi><mrow><mi>X</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>Y</mi></mrow></msub></math> apply between <math><mi>X</mi></math> and <math><mi>Y</mi></math>, and <math><msub><mi>C</mi><mrow><mi>Y</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>Z</mi></mrow></msub></math> between <math><mi>Y</mi></math> and <math><mi>Z</mi></math>:<math display=\"block\"><msub><mi>C</mi><mrow><mi>X</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>Y</mi></mrow></msub> = [(1, 1), (2, 1), (2, 2), (3, 1), (3, 2), (3, 3)]</math><math display=\"block\"><msub><mi>C</mi><mrow><mi>Y</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>Z</mi></mrow></msub> = [(2,1), (3,1), (3,2)]</math>After running AC-3, what is the domain of <math><mi>X</mi></math>?",
    "answers": [4],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "<math>{1,2,3}</math>",
      "<math>{2,3}</math>",
      "<math>{1,3}</math>",
      "<math>{1,2}</math>",
      "<math>{3}</math>",
      "<math>{1}</math>",
      "<math>{2}</math>",
      "<math>{}</math>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following (incomplete) game tree for tic-tac-toe. Tic-tac-toe is a two-player game where players \"x\" and \"o\" take alternating turns to place their respective symbols in an empty cell on the 3 x 3 game board, with the goal of getting three in a row (horizontally, vertically or diagonally):\nWhich one of the following statements is true?\n <img src=\"images/ibdzo.webp\" alt=\"tic tac toe\" />",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Player x is guaranteed to win",
      "Player o is guaranteed to win",
      "Player x can win, but only if player o plays suboptimally",
      "Player o can win, but only if player x plays suboptimally",
      "Either player can win, if the other player plays suboptimally",
      "Neither/none of the players can win"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following may be most useful in generation of a semantic network automatically from documents?",
    "answers": [3],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Information retrieval",
      "Sentiment analysis",
      "Syntactic parsing",
      "Information extraction",
      "None of the others."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary drawback of hill-climbing search?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "The search can get stuck in a local maximum",
      "The algorithm requires a lot of memory",
      "The search can get stuck in a global maximum",
      "The result depends strongly on the temperature schedule"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When we illustrate the Minimax algorithm, we use the symbols △ and ▽ for nodes in the search tree. A variation of the Minimax algorithm additionally uses the symbol ⃝ for some of the nodes. What does this symbol represent?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "A second opponent in a multiplayer game",
      "A game rule has been broken",
      "An element of chance in the game",
      "An estimated score, due to cutoff",
      "A tie between the players"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following researchers did not participate in the Dartmouth conference where the name \"artificial intelligence\" was coined?",
    "answers": [4],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "John McCarthy",
      "Marvin Minsky",
      "Herbert Simon",
      "Allen Newell",
      "Alan Turing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the main inference mechanism in semantic networks?",
    "answers": [2],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "Resolution refutation",
      "Generalized modus ponens",
      "Inheritance",
      "Skolemization",
      "De Morgan's law"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following would you choose as the unifier for <math>UNIFY(Loves(Per,x),Loves(y,z))</math>?",
    "answers": [0],
    "exam": ".*",
    "options": [
      "<math>(y/Per, x/z)</math>",
      "<math>(y/Per, x/Per, z/Per)</math>",
      "<math>(y/Per, x/z, z/Siri)</math>",
      "none of the above are suitable unifiers."
    ]
  }
]
